Hello everyone.
大家好！
My name is Mattie Porte.
我是玛缇 · 波特。
And we're recording today from Findhorn eco village
我们今天在苏格兰东北部的
in the northeast of Scotland.
芬迪霍恩生态村做录制。
Our focus today is the great turning.
我们今天的主题是大转折。
And to help us explore this important and relevant topic,
为了帮助我们探讨这一重要且有意义的主题，
we've invited an esteemed panel of guests, visionaries
我们邀请到几位尊贵的嘉宾和远见者，
who have dedicated their lives to the great turning
他们将自己的生命贡献给了大转折，
and to the evolution of human consciousness.
也贡献给了人类意识的进化。
So we are honored to have them with us.
我们很荣幸能够邀请到他们。
Craig Schindler
克雷格 · 辛德勒，
who coined the term the great turning in his book of
在他与格雷 · 拉帕特在1989年合著的《大转折》书中，
the same name, co-authored with Gary Lappet in 1989.
他创造了“大转折”这个术语。
Joanna Macy,
乔安娜 · 梅西，
who expanded and popularized the term through the work
她通过重建连接的工作及她所写的《积极希望》一书，
that reconnects and also through her book Active Hope.
推广并普及了 “大转折” 这一术语。
We also have Chris Johnstone with us
我们也邀请到第三位嘉宾克里斯 · 约翰斯顿，
who co-authored Active Hope with Joanna Macy
他与乔安娜 · 梅西合著了《积极希望》一书，
and developed a series of
并开发了一系列
companion workshops on that same topic.
专注于同样主题的工作坊。
We have David Korton,
我们还邀请到了大卫 · 克腾，
who wrote the Great Turning: from Empire to Earth Community.
他写了《大转折：从帝国到地球社区》一书。
We have Pat McCabe,
我们还邀请到了帕特 · 麦凯布，
woman stands shining of the Dine Nation
纳瓦霍族站着发光的女人，
who brings a unique indigenous perspective
她带来了独特的原住民视角，
and her work centers around thriving life and the great reunion.
她的工作以丰盛生命和大重组为中心。
We also have Duane Elgin,
我们也请来了杜安 · 埃尔金，
who recently wrote about the turning in his book
他最近在他的书中写到了大转折，
Choosing Life: Humanity's Great Transition
其书名是《选择生命：
to a Mature Planetary Civilization
人类迈向成熟星球文明的大转变》。
So thank you all for being with us.
感谢大家和我们在一起。
It is a pleasure and an honor.
我很高兴，也很荣幸。
So I'd like to start by asking our panel.
我想以提问来开始今天的交流。
What is the great turning?
这几个问题是：“什么是大转折?
What inspired you to this great work?
是什么感召你从事这项伟大的工作？
How are you seeing it manifesting in the world right now?
在你看来，这项工作在当今世界是如何显现的？
What is its significance in this moment in time?
在这个时间点上，它的意义是什么？”
Craig Schindler, author of the Great Turning: Personal Peace, Global Victory:
克里格·辛德勒，《大转折：个人宁静，全球胜利》的作者
And Craig let's start with you
克里格，从你开始吧，
as you first coined the term The Great Turning.
因为你首先创造了「大转折」这一术语。
Thank you, Mattie.
谢谢玛缇。
I think I'm going to begin with what motivated me
我想先聊聊是什么激励我开始，
and then go to the great turning.
然后再讲讲大转折。
As a youth I had the privilege of
作为一个年轻人，我有幸
hearing Dr. Martin Luther King JR.
聆听了马丁 · 路德 · 金博士的演讲。
I watched him take us up to the mountain top
我看着他将我们带到山巅之上，
where 2000 people in the auditorium leaned forward
礼堂里有2000多人前倾着身体，
and had a glimpse that it's possible for us to create
看到我们有可能在我们的星球上
the conditions for justice and peace on our planet.
为公正与和平创造条件。
Doctor King of course was echoing the great souls of
金博士当然是再现跨时代的伟大灵魂，
cross time who’d been to the mountain top,
那些灵魂曾经去过山巅，
looked down the quarters of time
回看这个时代，
and told us that an evolutionary shift is possible.
告诉我们进化的转变是可能的。
Then when my firstborn child the son was born
我第一个孩子是儿子，他出生在
on Hiroshima Day in 1981 in the midst of the cold war.
1981年日本广岛被原子弹轰炸日，当时正值冷战中期。
I juxtaposed holding this baby in my arm
当时我同时关注带娃、
with weapons of mass destruction and the beginning of
大规模杀伤性武器
climate change which we were aware of then.
以及当时我们就意识到的气候变化。
And the juxtaposition overwhelmed me
同时关注这三件事情让我不知所措，
in a way that I made a commitment to go to Los Alamos.
以至于我作出承诺，要去洛斯 · 阿拉莫斯。
And begin the process of creating a national dialogue
开始就降低核战争风险
on reducing the risk of nuclear war.
开展全国性对话。
And there at Bandelier and the ancient cave dwellings
在班德利尔和古老的岩洞里，
where people lived 1000 years ago
人们在 1000 年前居住的地方
indigenous inhabitants of this continent.
是这片大陆的土著居民。
They had a vision of the turning of the great turning.
他们有一个关于大转折到来的愿景。
And that the future generations that we are connected to
与我们相连的后代将
will give thanks and blessing to us for making the choice
感谢和祝福我们做出选择来创造一个
to create a more just, sustainable, compassionate world.
更加公正、可持续、富有慈悲心的世界。
And from then on
从那时起，
it's just been a matter of one foot after another,
我们只要走好每一步，
trying to do our best.
并努力做到最好即可。
So what is the great turning？
所以，什么是大转折？
It's the turning away from our self-destruction
它是将我们从自我毁灭
toward a new era of human dignity,
转向一个有人类尊严、
racial justice, environmental restoration,
种族正义、环境恢复和
and peace within and peace without.
内在宁静及外在和平的新纪元。
It's the end after 5000 years of
这是人类五千年来
our war weary adolescence
饱受战争之苦的青春期的结束，
where there's been some
在这段时间里，
major war pretty much the whole time.
几乎一直都有一些重大的战争。
To our conscious adulthood
对我们有意识的成年人来说，
it is a shift that is both personal
这是一个转变，
in terms of awakening to the inner, outer
它既是个人对内在的和外在的
connection of inter dependence and oneness
相互依赖性和一体性的觉醒，
and our kinship with all lives.
也是我们与所有生命的关系改变。
And it is the spiritual emergence of humanity
这是人类的灵性崛起，
to take responsibility to steward this beautiful planet.
承担起管理这个美丽星球的责任。
And to treat each other,
正如所有伟大的传统所言,
as all the great traditions say, with love and respect.
用爱和尊重，彼此相待。
How's it emerging now？
现在人类灵性崛起的如何？
I would say that this is
我认为当下是
the most pivotal time in human history
人类历史上最关键的时刻，
that many generations have looked at the future
许多代人都在看着未来，
and known that their decisions would affect the future.
并且知道他们的决定会影响到未来。
But that we are the first, those of us who are living now
但是，我们这些活着的人，
to look and see that the decisions we're going to make
首先会看到我们即将做出的决策
are going to determine whether there is a future or not.
会决定我们是否有未来。
And I would tell you that
而且，我要告诉你们，
the great turning is already happening.
大转折已经发生了。
It's been happening now for about 30 years
它已经发生了大约30年了，
that there are millions of people who are committed
有数百万人致力于
to love and compassion and dignity and stewardship.
爱、慈悲、尊严并负起责任。
And that we are working towards a tipping point.
我们正在向转折点迈进。
Scientists tell us that
科学家告诉我们，
when 10% of a population adopts an innovative idea
当人群中的10%采纳创新想法后，
that it becomes exponential.
变化将会呈指数级增长。
We're shifting from about 5% of us
当信息变得以指数级传播时，
who have a loyalty to all humanity and to our nation
我们正在从5%的人口
to our race our religion and to humanity to 10%
对全人类、对国家、对种族、
when the message will become exponential.
对宗教有忠诚度向10%改变的进程中。
Well, first I tried to...
首先，我试着...
make the definition of it
给大转折下个定义，
because I've come so used to with
因为我已经习惯了与
the folks around me using it…so.
我周围的人一起使用它。
I guess I define it as a perceptual
我定义大转折为一种感知
behavioral paradigm shift or revolution
行为模式的转变或革命，
that focuses on the emergence of
它聚焦在生命可持续
a life sustaining planetary culture and economy.
星球文明和经济的涌现。
The term, of course, was came in with Craig
当然, 这个术语来自克里格，
and it’s so wonderful to be sitting here with him.
和他坐在这里真是太好了。
And also my use of it
而且我使用这个术语
in the work that reconnects around the world was to…
在全球的重建连接工作坊中。
It was an expression coming out of Buddhism.
它是一种来自佛教的表达方式。
And so many Buddhist practices were borrowed from
在我们的工作中借鉴了
in our work that to represent teachings.
许多佛教实践来教学。
When the Buddha taught or set forth a worldview
当佛陀传法或阐明世界观时，
that was called a turning.
这被称为转法轮。
And it was he was turning the wheel of the dharma
而他就是在转动佛法的轮子，
the dharma chakra
即法轮。
And so, there were various turnings of it, the first turning.
有很多次转法沦，有初转法轮。
When he turned,
初转法轮后，
there was the second turning of the wheel and so forth.
还有二转法论等等。
This turning,
这次的转折，
the great turning I see as having the and we express it
也就是大转折，我看到它
as having the scope and magnitude of the
具有农业革命和
agricultural revolution and the industrial revolution
工业革命的范围和规模，
that thorough a change that which changed
它改变了我们触及到的一切，
touches everything the way we think,
我们的思维方式、
the way we act, the way we see.
行为方式和观察方式。
And in this one, the great turnings we've seen,
我们所看到的这个大转折，
as having three dimensions.
有三个维度。
Having a dimension of
第一个维度是
holding actions that is slowing the destruction
节制行动，这将减缓破坏。
And what so many people at the time we were starting
在我们开始的时候，很多人都认为
was identifying activism is that stopping things from
激进主义就是阻止事情的发生
happening, resisting that's no longer the case, is it?
以及抵制目前存有问题之处，是吗？
But the, the dimension that is so that's very important
但是，这个维度是非常重要的，
because we're keeping some of the gene pool
因为我们保留了一些基因库
as well as some of the species and
还有一些物种，
some of the key elements of the body of the earth.
以及地球主体的一些关键元素。
They …also there is…
第二个维度
our notions of great turning is building a new society.
是建立一个新社会。
In every respect the structures of it and the policies of it
在各个方面上建立，结构、政策、
and the way what we expect and what we give our lives to
我们期望的方式以及我们将生命奉献其中的事上。
And then, there is a deep inner revolution
第三个维度, 有一个深层次的内在革命，
as well of a shift in consciousness.
也就是意识的转变。
So I'm very grateful to be alive at this time
因此，我非常感恩能生活在这个时代，
and I give this my life.
并为此奉献我的生命。
Well,
好的，
one of the questions you ask was what inspired you and
你问的一个问题是：“什么激励了你”，
I think I like the question "Who inspired you".
我喜欢“是谁激励了你？”这个问题。
And that many people here
这里的许多人中，
I first heard about the great turning from Joanna
我最早是从乔安娜那里听到大转折
it was at…I can’t quite remember when it was.
是在…，我不太记得是什么时候了。
We started working
我们开始一起工作
together back in the 19 eighties at Findhorn in 1989.
是在一九八几年，1989年，在芬迪霍恩。
And, what really landed with me was an inspiring story.
真正打动我的是一个鼓舞人心的故事。
And I love the great turning
我热爱大转折，
because when I'm sunk by what I see happening
因为当我看到周围的事情而情绪低落时，
and there's so much that can leave you feeling sunk
有太多事情会让你觉得很无奈，
I think that the great turning is a way that things can go.
我认为大转折是可以让事情改变的一种方式。
And, I love the way.
而且, 我喜欢这种方式。
You were talking, Craig, about,
克里格，你在说：
"How people in the future might look back at",
“未来的人会怎样回看”，
"How things have gone".
“事情是怎么进展的”。
People turning up making a difference
人们现身，带来改变，
but also as well as the larger story
但还有更大的故事。
I love the question,
我喜欢这个问题：
What would it look like if the great turning were to happen
“如果大转折现在发生在我们身上，
through us right now that if we think of it as a process
如果我们认为它是一个过程，可以在任何时候发生在
that can happen through all of us in any moment.
我们所有人身上，那会是什么样子?”。
And I think that the different bit to that one is
我想这次大转折的不同点在于，
there's turning up to play our part
我们出现并在其中发挥作用，
and then in that turning up and seeing what's going on
同时看看事情是怎么发展的，
there's a turning away from that which causes harm and
有掉头离开引起伤害的情况，
a turning towards that which supports the flourishing of life
也有前行转向支持生命绽放的情况。
And I think of that as an organizing framework
我认为这象一个系统框架,
whenever I'm stuck and confused
每当我陷入困境、困惑
or sunk or feeling devastated
情绪低落或者觉得被彻底摧垮时，
I just think okay,
我就想，好吧，
What would the great turning look like
如果大转折现在就通过我发生，
if it was happening through me right now.
那会是什么样子呢？
It would involve me turning up.
这将涉及到我的现身。
We're turning up here.
我们都正在这里现身
And if you're listening to this,
如果你正在听这场座谈会
you're turning up and you're listening to this.
你就正在现身，因为你正在听我们的分享。
And you'll have conversations
当你出出现在这样的谈话中，
where you turn up in that conversation
你就会进行谈话。
And there might be things that you turn away from
有些事情，你可能会掉头离开;
and there might be things that you turn towards.
而有些事情，你可能会参与其中。
So, there’s a thought like,
因此，就有这样一个想法：
How does it happen?
“它是怎么发生的？”，
How do we see it being manifested?
“我们如何看到它显化的？”。
I love the idea of if you live it, then you'll find out
我喜欢这样的想法，“如果你活在其中，你就会发现”。
If you live the great turning
如果你活在大转折中，
you'll see what it looks like,
你将看到它是什么样子，
and it might be something really small and simple
这可能是一些非常小而简单的事情，
it might just be in a conversation
它可能就是一段谈话，
somebody says something
某人说了一些事，
you think I just want to say something in response to that,
你就想说些什么来回应，
I want to turn up here
我想在此现身起一定的作用，
or there might be something just simple
或者其它发生在你的花园
in your garden in your community
或社区的一些事情，
so anyway that's what I take it.
不管怎样，这就是我的理解。
It feels like it's an organizing story
感觉这是一个系统的故事，
that I find deeply inspiring.
让我深受启发。
And I'm really grateful for all of those
我衷心感谢所有我看到的
who I've seen living it
活在其中的人，
and I think I love what they're doing,
我热爱他们所作的事情，
I want to go that way,
我想踏上那条路，
so that's what I want to turn towards.
这是我想参与其中的。
And I'm so pleased to be alongside people here.
我非常高兴和在座各位在一起。
I see what you're doing
我看到你们正在做的事，
and I want to head that way
我想走上那条路，
I want to turn towards that way
我想转向那条路。
Pat McCable – Woman Stands Shining – Dine Elder, Proponent of the Indigenous Sciences of Thriving Life
帕特·麦凯布 – 站着发光的女人 – 迪恩·埃尔德，丰富生命的原住民科学的拥护者
(原住民语言）
So I'm introducing myself as a Dine woman to you.
好的，我把自己作为一名Dine女士介绍给你。
On this morning
今天早上，
from my mother's house here in Albuquerque New Mexico
在新墨西哥州阿尔伯克基我母亲家，
so that's where I find myself on this mother earth this morning.
这就是我今天早晨在地球母亲所待的地方。
And, then I was adopted into the lakota spiritual way of life
后来我被带进拉科塔的灵性生活方式，
and I was given the name yakpa najimi
我被取名为雅克帕·纳吉米，
which translates roughly to women standing shining.
简单翻译过来就是站着发光的女人。
So I wanted to greet you that way.
因此，我想以此来和你们打招呼。
So here I am an indigenous person on this panel and
在这里我是这星球上的原住民，
it might be surprising and it might not be,
长期以来我一直支持大崩溃，
to know that I've been rooting for collapse for a long time.
这一点也许会让你吃惊，也许不会。
I think most indigenous people on the planet
我认为这星球上的大多数原住民
have been rooting for collapse for a long time
长期以来都支持大崩溃，
so that's a very different orientation, right.
这是个非常不同的倾向，是吧？
Why have I been rooting for collapse?
为什么我一直支持大崩溃？
Well because one thing I say is I have this privilege of
这是因为，你知道我说过一件事，
walking in two different paradigms
我有幸行走在两个不同的范式之中，
completely different paradigms.
它们是完全不同的范式。
What do I mean by paradigm?
这里的范式指什么呢？
Different ways that human beings perceive
它是指人类对在这个
of being human on this mother earth
地球母亲上做人的不同认知，
in the exact same circumstances
在完全相同的情景下，
under the exact same sky
在同样的天空下，
same sun same water
同样的太阳和水，
but radically different views of how that is to be done.
但却是以完全不同的视角来看待这一切。
And so,
而且，
and there may be more than these two right.
可能还有两种以上的其它范式。
This is something that I feel like is really
这让我感到在这个时候
important at this time for us to consider
考虑到范式是一种选择
that paradigm is a choice.
是真正重要的事情。
Paradigm is a choice.
范式是我们的一个选择。
So I present indigenous paradigm in circumstances
在当下这个专题研讨会的情况下，
like the one we find ourselves here on this panel
我向大家展示原住民范式，
to say, it's not something that we can only imagine, or it's not a fantasy world, or a pipe dream
我们在说的不是想象的事、也不仅仅是童话世界或白日梦
so to speak it's like there are people doing it already.
而是在说已经有人在做的事。
So humans can absolutely do this we can witness them.
所以人类绝对可以做这些事，我们可以见证。
And so I think there's a longing and
我认为原住民有个渴望，
most indigenous peoples that I meet
我遇到的许多原住民，
for a return to what was before.
渴望回到从前。
And so this turning I would say
所以我会说这个大转折
is in some ways a turning backward
在某种方式上是
to another understanding and
回转到另一种理解，
to an awakening of of witnessing
回转到见证的觉醒上。
I guess I'll say the return of original instructions
我猜想我将会说回归到原始结构上
or the understanding of what, how exactly is
或者是理解这个地球到底
this earth construct made and what is our place in it,
是由什么构成，怎么构成的，我们在其中的位置是什么，
so I talk often about who we are where we are
因此，我经常谈论我们是谁，我们在哪儿，
how it is.
怎么样等等。
As Thich Nhat Hahn has pointed out
正如一行法师指出的，
he gives us a great indigenous word
他用英文给了我们一个伟大的
through the English language
原住民词语，
he calls us interbeing.
他称我们为“互在”。
We are so interrelated,
我们是如此相互关联，
so deeply interrelated.
如此深入地相互关联。
And so here's the spiritual dilemma is that
我们这里有个精神上的困境，
here we are in a free will construct
我们具有自由意志，
where everybody gets to do
每个人都可以
whatever the heck they dream up to do.
做自己梦想做的任何事。
And it's not only human species that
但是，并非只有人类这个物种
are involved in this free will business, it's all species.
参与到自由意志中，所有物种都参与其中。
I would say
但在这里，
but here we are human beings and with the power
我会这么说，我们是人类，有能力
and choice to do anything we can dream up.
而且有选择去做我们梦想的任何事。
And I love this meme that I've seen lately
我喜欢最近看到的这个模因，
and we choose white supremacy
我们选择了白人至上主义，
and credit scores of all the possibilities
并给所有可能性信用评分。
So, but we can make other choices, right?
但是，我们可以做出其它选择，对吗？
And so in this paradigm to understand
在这个范式里去理解
the great turning is the recognition of
大转折是要认识到
the laws of this construct
这种构建法则
and that is the spiritual dilemma is we
以及这里的精神困境是
can choose anything we want to do
我们可以选择我们想做的任何事
and every action that we commit
并且我们承诺的每个行动
affects every other being on the planet.
都会影响到这星球上的其它生命。
So what is your choice to be?
那么，你的选择是什么呢？
And I see I might at times I'll say one of the piece
我有时可能会说，
that you know for us we say that
对我们而言，
we've already passed through many worlds
我们已经经历了许多世界，
this isn't the first time we've lost a world
这不是我们第一次失去世界
or that we've been on the brink of losing a world.
或已经处于失去世界的边缘。
So that gives a different understanding spiritually,
因此，这让我在精神上、哲学上
philosophically about what is called for at this moment.
对此刻所召唤的东西有了不同的理解。
Duane Elgin, Author of Choosing Earth: Humanity’s Great Transition to a Mature Planetary Civilization
杜安·埃尔金，《选择地球：人类向成熟行星文明的大转变》的作者
To me the great turning  is a turn from death to life.
对我来说，大转折是一个从死到生的转折。
From death to life it's choosing life.
从死向生，这是选择生命。
Choosing earth is choosing life.
选择地球就是选择生命。
And in the west, the modern world,
在西方，这个现代世界，
has been living out of the paradigm of death, the dead universe
人们活在寂灭宇宙的范式中，
mostly dead matter and empty space,
大量充斥着死亡的物质和虚空的空间，
there for us to exploit from a place of separation.
我们在这样一个充满分裂的地方去争抢利益。
And now we're seeing room emerging from that mindset
现在我们看到心智模式涌现出转机的空间，
and so we're turning from a dead universe
我们正从一个死亡的宇宙
to a living universe.
转向一个生机勃勃的宇宙。
And as Pat suggested this is in many ways
正如帕特提到的，这在许多方面
is return to our most ancient understanding of
是转回到我们对所处宇宙的
现实本质的最古老的认识上。
the nature of reality of the universe in which we live.
It is a lie.
它是一个谎言。
And as we turn towards life，
当我们转向生命
we're coming home
我们是回家，
we're coming home to our original sense of being
回到本源的存在感，
and understanding of living in a living universe.
并意识到自己活在生生不息的宇宙中。
And I came to this decades ago.
我几十年前领会到这个。
Early on in my life,
在我生命早期，
I wanted to be a doctor, I wanted to be a healer.
我想成为医生，想成为疗愈师。
But in the early 19 sixties,
但是在二十世纪六十年代早期,
I began to see the deep wounding of humanity
我开始看到人类、
and the earth and the Vietnam era.
地球和越战时期的沉重伤痛。
And that is when I turn from being a healer of bodies and people
从那时起，我从一名身体疗愈师
to a healer of our wounded earth and our wounded future.
转变为一名疗愈地球和未来创伤的疗愈师。
So here we are, this is in my estimation.
所以我们来了，这是我的预测。
As people have said this is the most pivotal time
正如人们所说的，这是自上一个冰河时代
in the last 10,000 years since the end of the last ice age,
结束以来的最后一万年中最关键的时刻，
we are making now a turn back to our original nature
我们现在转回到我们的本性，
our original understanding of the universe
回到我们对宇宙的原始认识，
where we are and where we're going.
“我们在哪里？”，“我们要去向何方？”。
And where we're going is from separation
我们将从一个充满分裂和
and exploitation in a dead universe
剥削的垂死寂宇宙中走出来，
to connection communion and healing in a living universe.
去到一个有着连接、社区和疗愈的生机勃勃的宇宙。
And, in that turn,
在这个转折中，
we're turning towards care for the wellbeing of all life
我们转向关心所有生命的福祉。
David Korten, Author of The Great Turning: From Empire to Earth Community
大卫·克腾，《大转折：从帝国到地球社区》的作者
It's interesting as you frame the question that way.
你框定这样的问题很有意思。
What is the great turning?
什么是大转折？
And the first response that comes to my mind
我头脑中的最先反应是
it is the great turning of humanity.
这是人类的大转折。
From a course that leads to a world
从一个对任何人
that will not work for anyone
都不起作用的世界
to a world that works for everyone.
转向一个对任何人都起作用的世界。
And of course it has to be a world
当然，这必须是一个
that recognizes it is not just about people
认识到大转折不仅仅是关乎人类，
but it is about a living earth that birthed and nurtures us.
而是事关这个生养我们的生生不息的地球。
And our existence as well as our wellbeing
我们的生存和我们的福祉
depends on the health and wellbeing of the earth.
依赖于地球的健康和福祉。
In terms of the way we structure the economy
就我们构建经济及
and the way we define its purpose
设定经济目标的方式来说，
which is essentially to make lots of money for rich people
它本质上是要让富人赚到很多钱，
so that they can own everything on earth
这样他们能拥有地球上的任何东西，
that is leading us in the direction of self extinction.
而这将我们引入到自我灭绝的方向。
Now here's a simple truth
一个简单的真相是，
there are no winners on a dead earth.
在一个死亡的地球上没有任何赢家。
Wow.
哇。
We don't need a lot of scientific research and data
我们不需要很多科学研究和数据就知道这一点，
that's you know it is a self evident truth.
这是不言而喻的事实。
And yet it is the most fundamental truth
然而，对于这最根本的事实，
that almost everything in the way we manage
我们管理全球经济的方式
the global economy ignores and violates.
几乎都忽视和违反了这一事实。
So, it's very interesting as I reflect on this.
反思到这点很有趣。
I realize the way I came to this.
我意识到我是如何走到这一步的。
I grew up on a small town.
我生长在一个小镇。
My family owned a family business and I grew up
我们家是做生意的，在我长大的过程中，
assuming I was going to go back and run that business.
就设想我会回到家乡经营这个生意。
I didn't know if I'd ever leave my hometown and
我不知道我是否会离开我的家乡，
to end up with a life in which I've lived all over the world,
但最后我却到全世界各地生活，
in Africa Asia Latin America as well as in North America.
在非洲、亚洲、拉丁美洲以及北美洲等地生活。
I could not have imagined as a child
作为一个孩子时，我想象不到这个情景，
but the thing that took me to that was a recognition I was
但是让我走上这条路的是我意识到
a very, very conservative young republican that point.
我是一个非常、非常保守的年轻共和党人
And I was terribly concerned about
那时我非常担心
these communist revolutions born of poverty
由贫穷中产生的共产主义革命
that were a threat to our American way of life.
会给我们美国人的生活方式造成威胁。
As I think about that now,
现在看来，
my venture out into the world
我在世界范围内的冒险，
and a mission to end global poverty
并以终结全球贫困为使命
was an early kind of an early recognition
是一种早期的认识，
that if we don't create a world that works for everyone
那就是如果我们不创建一个适合所有人的世界，
we will have a world that literally will not work for anyone.
我们就会有一个对实际上不会适合任何人的世界。
And the rest of it is simply been a process of pushing,
那么, 接下来就是简单的推动过程，
pushing our understanding of
将我们对这一意义的
what that means to an ever deeper level.
理解推向一个更深的层次。
So what is the great turning?
那么，什么是大转折？
It is the transformation of humanity
它是人类从我们目前的
from our current misdirection toward the world
错误方向转向大多数
that most humans have dreamed of
人类梦想的世界的转变，
for it's a beginning of time,
因为这是一个和平、
a world of peace and love and generosity and caring.
爱、慷慨和关爱的时代的开始。
But it has to be a world on our finite earth,
但这种转变必须是发生在资源有限的地球上，
our finite living earth.
有限但又生机勃勃的地球上。
It has to be a world that is organized around
它必须是一个围绕
material sufficiency and spiritual abundance
物质充足和精神丰富而组成的世界，
rather than this insanity that we're all better off.
而不是一个疯狂的互相攀比的世界。
If we are all focusing our attention
如果我们都把注意力集中在
on making more and more money
赚更多更多的钱上，
so we can each increase our consumption in more and
我们每人都会以越来越多的
more  ridiculous and ultimately self defeating ways.
荒谬和最终自我毁灭的方式增加我们的消费。
Thank you.
谢谢你们！
So the word awakening was mentioned.
“觉醒”这个词被提到了。
When I've been researching
当我研究
the work of all of our panelists
所有嘉宾的工作时，
I've noticed that everything points to
我注意到每件事都指向了
this evolutionary leap of consciousness,
这种意识进化的飞跃,
this awakening if you will.
如果你愿意也可称为觉醒。
And I wonder if you can tell us
我想你们是不是愿意说说，
a little bit about how we achieve that,
“我们是怎么做到的？”，
what does it mean to awaken,
“觉醒意味着什么？”，
particularly for those who may be viewing
特别是对那些以后会看到今天讨论的人
this discussion later and maybe new to the spiritual path.
和那些刚刚听说灵性之路的人。
And then how is that awakening
并且，当下这个觉醒是
manifesting on the planet right now？
如何在这个星球上显化的？
And I'd like to start with Joanna.
我想请乔安娜先开始。
We're waking up to our true identity,
我们正在觉醒于我们的真实身份，
to who we really are
觉醒于我们的真实本性，
that's what I experience.
这是我所经历的。
And that's what I find this time is inviting us to do
这就是我发现这个时代正在邀请我们做的事情，
that we are essentially
我们本质上是，
and what we're waking up that identity is
我们正在意识到本质上
we are part of earth,
我们是地球的一部分，
we are being earth.
我们就是地球本身。
Choosing to come home,
选择回家，
to that identity as earth is what we long for
选择回到这个地球身份，都是我们渴望的。
We have been separated for so long
我们已经分离的太久了，
we have been separated
我们已经分离...
especially by the last…, it's gone on a long time
很长时间了
and something we could go way back to… beginnings
这可以追溯到
as Friedrich Angles said the private property.
弗雷德里西·安吉尔所说的私人财产。
But that we have been isolated from each other
但是，我们在一个世纪以来，
in a century’s… of hyper individualism
都处于高度个人主义，彼此孤立分离，
and expressing and taught how to express that
我们用比较的方式表达，
in terms of the comparing mind
我们也被教着用比较的方式表达，
in terms of seeing that we are… have this private turf
我们用这样的方式看待个人的所有物，
that we can with comparing mind
我们用比较心，
compare to what others have.
和别人拥有的相比较。
In this sense of exposure of a small separate fragile self
在这方面，展露出一个小小的、孤立的、脆弱的自我，
so that we are waking up to being earth herself
我们正在觉醒于我们是地球本身。
And what's wonderful here is that
这里奇妙的是，
at this point these two great rivers
在这一点上，两条大河
that have been separated for so long.
已经分离许久许久了。
Science and spirituality or science and religion
科学与灵性，是科学与宗教,
are flowing together.
正汇聚到一起。
To show us in each their different ways
它们以各自不同的方式向我们展示
spiritual practice and traditions
灵性实践和传统，
as well as systems thinking, gaia theory.
还有系统思考和盖娅理论。
And gaia bringing us to experience
盖娅让我们去亲历，
that we are our earth and we are earth.
我们是我们的地球，我们就是地球。
Our earth becoming conscious of
地球开始意识到
ourselves and our true self
我们以及我们的真我。
So this is not a creed.
这并不是宗教信条。
And this is not something that's a required belief
这不是需要信念的事儿，
but it just is a beginning to emerge a waking up.
这仅仅是觉醒出现的开端。
And that changes everything.
这将改变一切万有。
And as that as that happens
在它发生的时候，
we are beginning to experience
我们开始体验到
that other people are speaking our minds with us
其他人会跟我们讲相同的想法，
that there's a collective dimension of
我们的智慧和创造力
our intelligence and our creativity
有一个集体的维度，
that we are coming home from a long long time.
经历这么久，我们走在了回家的路上。
And it feels good.
这种感觉很好。
It's waking up
这就是觉醒。
617 00:30:17 Chris
I think there's a different word I prefer
我想我喜欢另一个词，
and it's belonging.
那就是归属。
I suppose awakening is about there's a sense of
我想觉醒是关于有一种感觉，
there was something that I was asleep to that
那就是我曾有一些沉睡的东西，
I'm now becoming more aware of or conscious of or living
现在变得更加能自我觉察，或是鲜活起来
but in terms of what I'm becoming more aware of
但就我变得更加觉察而言，
what I'm feeling stronger inside me it's belonging.
我的内心感觉更加强烈，那就是归属。
And as Joanna was saying it's like recognizing that
如乔安娜所说，这就象认识到
we're part of life on earth we're part of earth.
我们是地球上生命体的一份子，是地球的一份子。
But it's more than that,
但它不止于此，
because I think with belonging
因为我认为有了归属感，
also comes a sense of direction and purpose
也就有了方向感和目的感，
like if I feel I belong to a family
比如说如果我觉得我属于一个家庭，
I belong to a community
属于一个社区，
I belong to a team
属于一个团队，
that shapes the whole story of my life what I'm about,
这塑造了我是什么\
what I'm aiming to do and that when I feel.
我想做什么以及我何时感受到的全部生命故事。
Strength of belonging
归属的力量，
from that comes loyalty
由此而来的忠诚
I want to show up and act for the team that I'm part of
我想表达出来，为我所属的团队而行动，
I feel like I'm part of the team, here today with all of you.
今天在这里，和你们在一起，我感到我是这团队的一员。
Some I've met and
有些人见过，
some I've met through the work that you've been doing
有些人是通过你们所做的工作而认识你们。
So awakening is also a process.
觉醒也是一个过程。
It's something that we can help happen more.
觉醒是一件我们可以让它更多次发生的事。
And in the same with belonging,
归属感也是如此，
it's not like we just belong,
不只是归属感，
and we're in it and it's an either or thing
我们身在其中，这是非此即彼之事，
it's something that we can grow
而是可以发展我们
our sense of belonging here on our world.
在这世界上的归属感。
And I come across people sometimes
我有时会遇到这样的人，
who have such a sense of like not belonging
它们感觉没有归属，
that they feel the sense of alienation
他们感觉到疏离，
that leaves them feeling that they've lost the plot.
让他们觉得自己已经失去了意义。
And I know that I felt like that in the past too.
我知道我过去也有这种感觉。
But when I do feel belonging
但是当我有归属感时，
it's like I know what I'm here to do
我就知道自己在这里做什么，
because I know what I'm here to act for.
因为我知道自己在这里为什么而行动。
I really appreciated
我非常感谢
what Chris was just saying about belonging.
刚刚克里斯讲到了归属。
And to me,
对我来说
the awakening is coming home
觉醒意味着回家，
as coming home to our original home
回到我们本初的家，
which is the aliveness of a living universe.
那就是生生不息的宇宙的活力。
And we have been living in this place of
我们一直生活在这个
what we thought was dead matter and empty space
我们认为充满死寂物质和荒芜空间的地方，
without meaning or purpose.
没有意义或目标。
And now through the lens of physics
现在，通过物理学镜头，
as well as the ancient wisdom traditions were seeing now
以及古老的智慧传统，我们看到，
we are living in a place of great and profound aliveness
我们生活在一个伟大而深奥的充满活力的地方，
and we're coming home
我们正在回家，
not only to the aliveness of the earth
不仅是回到地球的活力中，
but the aliveness of the universe itself.
也是回到宇宙本身的活力之中。
And so when our aliveness within
因此，当我们的内在活力
meets the extraordinary aliveness without
遇到超凡的外在活力时，
we're coming home,
我们就在回家，
life is meeting life.
生命遇见着生命。
And in that meeting we feel belonging.
在这相遇中，我们感受到了归属。
We feel finally,
我们终于觉得，
we can relax at where we should be, want to be.
自己可以在我们应该之地或渴望之地放松下来了。
And that's at home in the greater aliveness of
这就是地球和宇宙的
the earth and the universe and within ourselves.
大活力以及我们自己的家。
So, the awakening is a return to belonging.
所以，觉醒是对归属感的回归。
To me, the foundation of our awakening
对我来说，我们觉醒的基础是
is an awakening to the actual nature of life
认识到生命的真实本质，
and its complexity and its interdependence
以及生命的复杂性和相互依赖性。
What we're discovering it now, the frontiers of science
我们在当今前沿科学中发现了
truth long denied or ignored by science.
长期以来被科学否认或忽略的事实。
We're coming back actually to
我们实际上回到了
fundamental insights of our earliest ancestors.
我们祖先的根本洞见上。
One of my very close colleagues from South Africa
我有一位来自南非的关系亲密的同事，
talks about the traditional South African word "Ubuntu"
他讲起一个传统的非洲词，即“Ubuntu”，
which means I am because you are.
意思是“你在故我在”。
Wow.
哇。
That is a very simple statement of it.
这是一个非常简单的表达。
But in the bigger sense I am because all of life is.
但在更大的意义上，众生在故我在。
And if the interactions between all these living beings stop
而且如果众生间的相互作用中止的话，
we are dead
我们就死了。
Oh, again there are no winners on a dead earth.
哦，再说一次，在一个死亡的地球上, 没有赢家。
But here's where we also need to,
但这里也是我们需要的地方，
to be aware of the unfolding of creation
我要意识到创造力的展开过程，
as we increasingly understand it in some ways.
因为我们在某些方面越来越了解它了。
It sounds like genesis
这听起来象创世纪，
but the way science describes it
但是科学描述它的方式是
we started out with this burst of an energy cloud or
我们是从这个能量云的爆炸开始，
the unitary consciousness or whatever you want to call it
或从一体意识开始，不论你怎么称呼它，
but it's like a burst-forth
它就象在探索
on a journey to discover its possibilities.
可能性旅程上的一个突然爆发。
Because the way we understand the unfolding of creation
因为我们通过我们现在的科学理解
through our, now scientific understanding,
来理解创造的展开，
it's not the winding down of entropy toward energy death
创造不是熵值逐渐下降走向能量死亡，
it is the whole of creation as we know
它是我们所知的整个创造，
it is a winding up toward ever growing complexity,
它是走向不断增长的复杂性的过程，
It's an unfolding and we are a part of that process.
它在不断展开中，而且我们是这过程中的一部分。
And part of what what we have to wake up to,
我们必须清醒地认识到，
all the ways in which we currently organize
我们目前在文化信仰方面的
in terms of our cultural beliefs
所有组织方式，
which are so polluted and distorted by the economics.
都被经济严重污染和扭曲了。
We teach our children
我们教孩子们的是，
that I call egonomics not economics.
我称之为“自我学”而非“经济学”。
And it is that promotion of the ego and
这种学问推崇自我、
the individual wealth and the individual consumption
个人财富和个人消费
and my getting it better than you.
以及我比你做得更好。
The focus on competition
它注重竞争，
rather than the recognition of our interdependence
而不是认识到我们之间的相互依赖关系
and the essential importance of cooperation.
及合作的根本重要性。
It tells me something about the variety of human possibility
这告诉我人类可能性的多样性，
that we can create that which is in our mind.
我们能将头脑中的东西创造出来。
And if we can imagine the world we want
如果我们能想象一个想要的世界，
we can create the world we want.
我们就能把它创造出来。
I've been privileged to be in the room several times
我有幸几次和DALAI喇嘛在同一会场，
and watch the dalailama come in to the room
看到他走进房间，
sometimes in a small group
有时候在一个小团体，
sometimes solo large group.
有时候是非常大的团体。
And he comes in laughing and bowing
他进来的时候边笑边鞠躬，
laughing and bowing probably 20 times
在他走上讲台之前，
before he gets up to the stage.
可能得有20次。
And I like to think
我会想，
that he's laughing and bowing because he gets the joke
他的笑和鞠躬是因为他听到笑话吗，
because he sees from his perspective that
是因为从他的角度他看到
everyone in the room has the light
房间里的每个人
of consciousness within them.
都有内在的意识之光。
Everyone in the room and
对房间里的每个人，
he gets to play the role of the one who's reflecting that.
他扮演“镜子”的角色来将这点反映出来。
And he knows that if he were to stop and say yo
他知道如果他停下来打招呼，
I'm dalailama at that moment he wouldn't be the dalailama.
说“我是DL喇嘛”，那他就不是DL喇嘛。
Because each one of us
因为我们每人的
has that light of consciousness in us
内心都有觉醒之光，
and we share it with all sentient beings
我们与所有有情众生共享这份光。
Right now we're going to kind of tran-state culturally.
此刻，我们正在迈向一个文化变革。
The trance of ego,
迷恋自我，
the trance of small self
迷恋小我，
that objectifies self and others
会把自我与他人客体化，
and creates that sense of isolation
并会产生孤立感、
alienation and really destruction.
疏离感以及真正的摧毁。
We need to awaken from that space in the now right now
我们需要立即从此时此地
to the big soul
觉知到大我，
to the soul to the witness and consciousness
觉知到灵魂、见证和意识，
that sees and experiences our interbeing
看到并亲历我们的互在，
as Joanna said quoting Thich Nhat Hahn
正如乔安娜引用的一行禅师的话，
our interrelatedness
我们与所有生命
our ecological connection
都内在相连、有着生态连接
our spiritual oneness with all life
以及有着灵性上的合一。
The great turning has four levels.
大转折有四个层次。
The recognition that we are one earth.
认识到我们都同属一个地球。
Our life is interdependent.
我们的生命是彼此相依。
The recognition that we are one family.
认出到我们是一家人。
Evolve from one archetype mother
大约20万年前
about 200,000 years ago.
从一个母性原型进化而来。
The recognition that we have one abiding vision
认识到我们有一个持久的愿景，
and all our traditions is to create the conditions
我们所有的传统都是为了
for peace within and with the earth.
内心平安以及地球和平而创造条件。
And the recognition that there is one shared global ethic
认识到有一个全球共同道德准则，
which is the ethic of reciprocity to treat the other,
也就是以互惠准则对待彼此，
all life with the love and respect that you want for yourself.
用你想自己得到的那种爱与尊敬去对待所有生命。
Thank you.
谢谢！
I again here I said I'm rooting for collapse.
我再次说我支持崩溃。
Collapse of what?
什么崩溃呢？
I'm rooting for the collapse
我支持的崩溃是，
of the super imposition of a certain understanding
在这个神圣的、
of humanity's role in this interbeing
相互依存的生命圈，超级强加
on this sacred hoop of life.
某种理解于人类作用的崩溃。
And so as we begin to recognize
我们开始意识到
what it means to be an interbeing,
互在意味着什么，
to have every one of our actions affect every other being
我们的每一个所作所为都会影响到其他任何人，
that is giving some of us pause, not everybody.
这会给一些人带来暂停，不过不是每个人都会停下来。
But some of us are recognizing,
但一些人正在意识到，
wow, what does that mean?
哇！这意味着什么？
And one thing that I'm really noticing in this awakening is
在这样的觉醒中，我真正注意到的一件事是，
that there's a lot of co-witnessing going on that has been,
许多共同见证正在进行着，
I don't know, if we can say unprecedented
我不知道是否可以称为史无前例。
But it's certainly been a long time
但这确实是很长时间以来才出现的一件事。
And I'm going to say with the murder of
我要说说发生在美国的
George Floyd here in the United States.
乔治·弗洛伊德谋杀案。
It's not that black communities
不是黑人群体
didn't know that this was going on
不知道发生了什么
this has been going on for them for a long time.
这种情况在他们身上发生很长时间了。
And suddenly,
然而突然间，
all these other communities are saying,
所有其他群体都在说：
What？A policeman can kneel down on a person's neck,
什么？一个警察竟然能跪在一个人的脖子上,
and broad daylight, and be filmed.
在光天化日之下, 而且被拍下来。
How did this happen? What?
这到底是怎么发生的？怎么回事？
With the discovery of the mass graves of the children
随着加拿大寄宿学校
in the residential boarding schools in Canada
大量儿童乱葬坑的发现，
which was actually a carry over from the uk
这实际上是从英国遗留下来的，
they're finding mass graves in Ireland and Scotland as well.
他们也在爱尔兰和苏格兰发现了乱葬坑。
So that practice was carried to the United States and
这种方式也被带到了美国，
posed on indigenous peoples here.
施加在了原住民身上。
But this discovery of these mass graves of the children
在天主教学校和寄宿寄宿学校中
at the catholic schools, the residential boarding schools
发现了大量儿童的集体坟墓，
where the children were forcibly kidnapped
这些儿童被强行绑架
and taken away from their families.
并从家人身边带走。
As a methodology of subduing
作为一种征服的手段,
and bringing them into
突然逼迫他们与
alignment with modern world paradigm suddenly
现代世界的范式保持一致，
it's not that indigenous people
并不是原住民
didn't know that was happening,
不知道发生了什么，
my parents and grandparents
我的父母和祖父母
went to those residential boarding schools.
都去了这种寄宿学校。
I'm the first generation out in my family who didn't go.
我是我们家族中第一代没去寄宿学校的。
It didn't happen a long time ago it's recent.
这不是很久以前的事情，就发生在最近。
And so this co-witnessing
这种共同见证，
and this outcry and this outrage
这种大声疾呼和愤怒，
and this collective warning
以及这种共同警示，
what we have been capable of doing to each other.
是我们能为彼此做的。
It is like we're waking out of a trance
这就象从恍惚中醒来，
and seeing what has happened.
看看发生了什么。
It was actually at Finnhorn during the new story summit
在芬迪霍恩的新故事峰会上，
that when I got overwhelmed at one point
有某个时点上，我不堪重负，
I went out and sat on the dunes to just collect myself
我走了出去，坐在沙丘上，调整一下我自己。
The holy people came to me and I said
有个圣人走过来，对我说，
rather than try to tell a new story from this point forward
与其从现在开始讲一个新的故事，
you would be better off retelling the old story.
不如重述旧故事。
And if you went back and retold the old story
如果你回去重讲老故事，
you would automatically change
你会自动地改变
the trajectory into the future.
通往未来的轨道。
Wow, so I've been working with that a great deal and so,
哇！我在这方面做了大量的工作，因此，
in many ways I feel like this co-witnessing
在许多方面，我觉得这种共同见证
is the retelling of the old story on one level.
在某种角度上而言是在重述老故事。
So I'm learning I'm asking I'm in spiritual inquiry,
我在学习，我在询问，我在灵性上探究，
asking what does it mean to retell the old story.
询问重述老故事意味着什么。
But I have this sense that this co-witnessing
我感知到这就是共同见证，
because these stories have been running without witness
因为那些故事里没有见证人
without the necessary witnesses
没有能够带来疗愈，
to bring healing and to bring reckoning.
带来清理所需的见证人。
And so I'm going to say,
因此，我要说，
also the awakening is to realize that
这种觉醒是意识到
we have surprising allies at this time.
此刻我们有让我们感到震惊的同盟。
Can we accept that？
我们能接受吗？
Can we accept the surprising allies
我们能接受这些
that we find ourselves with
让我们震惊的同盟吗？
And I'm going to include in this.
我会把他们包含进来。
When we did ceremonies in Europe
当我们在欧洲举行仪式
to address what took place during the witch hunts
来处理猎杀女巫期间发生的事情时，
which the spirits call an archetypal wounding of humanity.
这在灵性上被称之为人类的伤害原型。
I encountered in a cathedral in Salvia,
在塞尔维亚的一个大教堂，
the spirit of King Ferdinand
我遇到了国王斐迪南的灵魂。
And he came to me in that place and he said,
在那里他走过来，对我说，
tell me what to do now,
“告诉我现在该做什么？”，
tell me what I can do now.
"告诉我现在能做什么？”.
I mean I can't tell you how shocking that was to me.
我简直不知道怎么告诉你，我当时有多震惊。
King Ferdinand wants to understand
斐迪南国王想了解
how to undo what was done.
如何挽回所做的一切。
So we don't know who our allies are
我们不知道我们的同盟是谁
even from the spirit world, right?
即使是来自灵性世界，是不是？
For all I know General George Armstrong Custer
就我所知，乔治·阿姆斯特朗·卡斯特将军
is standing right by my side,
就站在我身边，
saying, Go Pat, go.
对我说，“加油，帕特，冲！”
I don't know.
而我对此一无所知。
So we're going to have an opportunity now
我们现在有个机会
to touch a little bit more on what you just introduce.
来多讨论下你们刚才所提及的内容。
And so this question surrounds the adversity that we face.
这个问题围绕着我们面临的困境。
And the increasing adversity we are about to face
人类造成的灾难性气候变化、
through the effects of catastrophic climate change
人为造成的气候变化以及
human made, human caused climate change and
包括我们自己在内的大规模物种灭绝的威胁，
the threat of mass species extinction including our own.
让我们将面临越来越多的逆境。
And I know that you have all done to varying degrees
我知道你们已经在不同程度上
profound workshops and you've designed healing spaces.
在做一些深度的工作坊或者疗愈空间。
And Joanna through the work that reconnects
乔安娜通过重建连接工作
that gives us a process
给我们提供了一个过程，
through which to grieve and
通过它去哀悼和
experience our pain and loss for world and crisis.
体验我们失去的世界或面临的危机。
I'd like to start with Duane this time.
这次我想请杜安先开始。
Because Duane in your book
因为在你的书中，
you beautifully juxtaposition
你美妙地并列了
the possibility of both hope and despair.
希望和绝望的可能性。
And that we as humanity are facing a choice.
这是我们作为人类正面临的选择。
So can you say more about that.
因此，关于这点，你能多说一些吗？
What are the skills and practices that we need to cultivate?
我们需要培养哪些技能和实践？
Well you've mentioned Joanna's work
你刚提到乔安娜的工作，
looking at the grieving of what is being lost
看到对我们所失事物的悲伤，
I think that is foundational.
我认为这是基础。
Until we open and allow into
直到我们敞开心扉，允许我们
our heart our soul what is being lost,
走进内心和灵魂，去感受我们失去了什么，
not simply being lost to humans
不单纯是人类失去的，
the loss of life of plants and animals
也有动植物生命中所失去的
and their future as well.
还有它们的未来。
There's upwards 1 million species
多达超过一百万物种
that will be extinct by the end of this century.
在本世纪末将灭绝。
And so if we can open to the loss
因此，如果我们能面对这些失去，
and allow that grieving to enter
允许悲伤进入到
into our hearts and our beings
我们的内心和存在，
that then is a coming home to reality.
那就是回到现实的本质。
And out of that recognition of reality
当我们认识到这个本质
we can then give our unique gifts to healing the world.
我们就可以献出自己独具的天赋来疗愈这个世界。
And so the second part
因此，第二部分，
I think would be finding our true gifts
我认为是发现自己真实的天赋，
it may be gifts of music, an art
可能是音乐，也可能是艺术，
and of spiritual practice and so on.
或灵性实践等等。
We each come into this world with unique and true gifts.
我们每个人都是带着独有和真实的天赋来到这个世界。
And so there's no specific remedy that I am suggesting
我没有建议具体的补救措施，
but rather to agree what is being lost to look within at what
而是认可正在失去的东西，
can be gained by what we can give back to the world that
去看看我们能从回馈世界中得到什么，
would be my core suggestion for our moving to healing
这是我对走向疗愈的核心建议。
As I recall some wonderful moments and
我回想起在芬迪霍恩的
wondrous moments at Findhorn where
一些美好且奇妙的时刻，
we were able to do that in very large numbers actually
在那里非常多的人一起做活动
where we brought…
我们带来的
this is not just my solitary, my pain as Bill, Joe or Emma,
不仅是自己作为比尔、乔或艾玛的孤独和伤痛，
but that this is a species moment
那更是一个物种的时刻，
this is all of us as a moment
这是一个我们所有人的时刻，
or particularly this is a moment of
对于我们这些被认为
those of us who have been identified with the privileged
是有特权的人来说，这是一个特别的时刻，
that we can get own property and
因为我们有自己的领地，
go to places like Findhorn or
能来到像芬迪霍恩这样的地方
so the opening to the loss to do it together.
大家一起面对所失去的，一起做这件事。
And to find what as you sense that we are many
我们发现，也感受到，
in this horror of and guilt as well that it makes it,
我们许多人都在恐惧和愧疚之中，
you can see that there is something very deep about it
你能看到这里有很深刻的东西，
that we are inviting a massive opening of the heart
我们在邀请一个巨大的心扉敞开，
and a creative way even of articulating them
甚至以一种创造性的方式去表达他们，
letting it pour out in movement and gesture
让它在动作和姿态中倾泻而出，
or as in painting in words
或者用绘画或言语来表达，
to let it to build a monumental expression
让它建立一个丰碑式的表述，
that can change who we are
这可以改变我们是谁，
can lift us up to a larger identity
可以把我们提升到达一个更大的身份，
that can see the path we've been on.
可以看到我们所走过的道路。
And in that we cannot be silenced,
在那里，没有人能让我们沉默，
so many people and
有许多人，
particularly in my culture in the United States
特别是在我身处的美国文化中，
where we have been we pathologize
我们一直以来都在病理化，
and that has served the power holders
这对权力持有者有利，
that has been successful in people
他们成功地让人们
allowing their grief, and their horror to be pathologized
将自己的悲伤和恐惧病态化处理，
and that certainly serves them with
这就肯定在为权力拥有者服务，
they get prescriptions and it served the big pharma.
他们得到了处方，这对大药厂有利。
No end.
这条路没有尽头。
That becomes a something very creative that
一些非常有创造力的事情正在出现，
stirs the very depths of one's consciousness
它们激发一个人的意识深处，
and find a unity in that, and that we are and a creativity
并在其中找到统一性和创造力，
that we can then and the unity we find
然后在这种悲痛中
suddenly in this grief is a unity that
我们突然发现统一性是
we can find, to change, and rebuild.
我们可以找到的，可以改变的和重建的。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I've actually witnessed those
我实际上在芬德霍恩
sessions together in the universal hall
这里的通用大厅里
here at Findhorn that you spoke of.
见证了你所说的那些会议。
And they were profoundly healing
这些会议有深刻的疗愈力，
and opened up a gateway from me
它为我打开了一扇大门，
and gave permission to feel
允许我去感受
whatever the emotion was to feel.
可以感觉到的任何情绪。
And your right to do that together
你们现在一起分享
is astonishing and powerful.
真是令人惊异而有力的。
Thank you for your great work.
为你们伟大的工作而感谢你们。
I knew if I posed this question
帕特，我知道如果我提出这个问题，
it would cause me to feel deeply and
会引起我的深切感受，
also listening to some of the things you were saying, Pat,
也会听到你说的一些事情，
about the enormous adversity facing
自古以来，
indigenous peoples throughout
或者说自白人到来之后，
since the beginning of time
土著人民一直
or since the arrival of the white men, let's say.
面临着巨大的逆境。
And I know that you've done
我知道你做了
some beautiful rituals and healing ceremonies.
许多美好的疗愈仪式。
And I wonder what wisdom you have to share with us
我想知道你有什么智慧可以与我们分享，
what have you learned about how to face adversity that
你在如何面对逆境方面学到了什么，
might benefit others viewing our session today.
这将为观看今天分享的人们带来帮助。
1076 Pat
Thank you yeah,
谢谢！是的，
I'm remembering our global wiping
我记得在新故事峰会期间，
off the tears ceremony at Findhorn
我们在芬德霍恩
during the new story summit.
举行全球拭去眼泪仪式。
Wow.
哇!
Well, you'll notice I keep speaking about paradigm
你注意到我一直在说范式，
so for me you know redefining our context is key.
对我来说，重新定义我们的背景是关键。
And the reason that I participate in so many talks and panels is
我参加那么多会谈和专题讨论会的原因
I'm not interested in being cultural show and tell.
并不是我对社交和讲话感兴趣。
But I want to propose that sustainability is the highest
而是我想提出可持续性是
and most sought-after technology on the planet.
地球上最高和最广受欢迎的技术。
Who should we be talking to?
我们应该和谁谈论？
We should be talking to those peoples who've known
我们应该与那些知道
how to live in one place, an extended period of time
如何在一个地方生活很长时间的人交谈，
1000 years, 5000 years, 10,000 years, 20,000 years
他们生活了一千年、五千年、一万年或两万年，
in relative health, harmony and happiness.
生活在相对健康、和谐、快乐之中。
so I want to keep bringing that to us.
因此，我一直想将这些带给我们。
And so we were talking about the guilt
我们目前在讨论作为人类
and shame of being human right now.
感受到的愧疚和羞耻。
So I say we have low self esteem as a species right now.
我会说作为一个物种，我们此刻正处于低自尊状态。
Because we have this belief that
因为我们有着这样的信念，
everything we touch we destroy right now.
即我们正在毁灭每一个触碰到的东西。
So I want to point to something
我想指出的是，
this actually comes out of my daughter, Lila June's work.
这其实来自我女儿利拉 · 琼的工作。
She's getting her PHD
她正在攻读博士学位，
and traditional land management practices.
她研究传统土地管理方式。
She's pointing this out to me,
她给我指出来，
but I'll say it this way,
但我会这样讲，
so remember what we're taught in the history books
记得我们在历史书上所学的吧
even I was taught this in the history books
甚至我也是在历史书上学的，
when those ships came and touched on this continent
当那些船到达并触碰到这块大陆时，
it didn't matter where they touched, South America
触碰到哪里并不重要，他们叫它南美洲
what we call North America.
我们叫它北美洲。
What did they always see?
他们都看到了什么呢？
They always were stunned and
当他们到达时，
amazed at what they saw when they arrived
总是会被自己看到的景象惊愕到，
it was lush, it was fruiting, it was flowering
那里郁郁葱葱、果实累累、鲜花盛开、
the game was plentiful etc.
活动多姿多彩等等
They couldn't believe their eyes,
他们不敢相信自己的眼睛，
they had just they had landed on Eden.
他们刚刚到达了伊甸园。
But the implication in that story that
这故事隐含的意思，
has so gripped humanity psyche is
并抓住人类心理的是
that it was un-despoiled by human touch, right?
它没被人类活动而破坏，是吗？
Because if it had been touched by humans,
因为如果它被人类触碰，
it would’ve looked like where they came from.
它就会变成这些人类所来自地方的样子。
Well the truth is
真相是
there were millions of people on the continent
这块大陆上有几百万人
there were millions of humans on this continent
so imagine that there was a way to be human here
想象一下，这里有一种做人的方式
such that we could cause all life to thrive.
就是我们能让所有生命茁壮成长。
So again it's not a fantasy
所以我想再次强调一下，这不是幻想，
it's not a fantasy.
这并不是幻想。
And also we have social technologies
而且我们有社交技术，
so we have people with completely different cosmologies
有具有完全不同宇宙观的人们，
completely different languages
有着完全不同的语言，
completely different understanding of
对男女角色
what masculine feminine roles were
有完全不同的理解，
living side by side.
我们并肩生活在一起。
So we have social technologies so we have that capacity
我们有社交技术，我们有能力，
we can actually deal with diversity.
我们其实可以应对多元化。
It's not inherent in us.
这不是我们与生俱来的。
So one other thing that I wanted to bring up here is
我想在这里提到的另一件事是，
what I've been saying to activists for a while is
我对活动家们说了好一阵子的话是，
we do have to simultaneously prepare for
我们确实需要同时为
war and peace at the same time.
战争与和平做好准备。
War means standing in our descent
战争意味着站在低处
and declaring clearly what we give our consent to
清晰地宣布我们同意什么，
and what we do not give our consent to
不同意什么，
that is spiritually huge huge huge.
这在灵性上是巨大、巨大、巨大的。
We must do that
我们必须这么做，
whether we believe anybody's
不论我们是否相信
going to do anything about it or not
人们会不会这么做，
because it sets certain spiritual laws into motion
因为这让灵性法则付诸行动，
which I won't go into in my short time here
因时间原因这次不会讲太多，
but I'm going to say that's very important
但我会说那非常重要。
And peace because as the earth changes come
和平也很重要，因为随着地球变化的发生，
a willingness is going to be sweeping the land
有一种意愿吹拂大地，
which it already is willingness
这意愿已然发生，
and more willingness and more willingness
之后将有更多更多的意愿，
as the realization of what the falseness of
因为人们认识到当代
the modern world paradigm has been… comes to bear.
世界范式的虚假和随之而带来的压力。
And so that's why we have to stay spiritually fit
这就是为什么我们必须保持灵性上的健康，
as we have to be able to receive our former enemy
因为我们必须能够接受我们以前的敌人，
as that willingness and
因为这种意愿和
that dawning realization sweeps over them.
恍然大悟拂过了他们。
We have to be able to receive them
我们必须能接受
and take them in and become interbeing.
并包容他们，我们彼此相互依存。
And the last thing I'll say is
最后我要说的是，
I started out being raised
我是在荷兰
in the Dutch Christian reform church
基督教改革教会长大的，
because that's how my parents were raised
因为那是我父母被抚养的地方，
those were the missionaries that
是传教士
took them into the residential boarding school.
将他们带到寄宿学校。
And so I do have visitations just same as other spirits
我会被象布法罗·卡费尔曼
like Buffalo Caffelman or the corn mothers.
或玉米母亲那样的灵魂所探望。
I have visitations from the Christ.
我也有来自基督的探望。
And he has talked to me and he has said,
他和我谈话，他说:
we are in a dark age
“我们在黑暗时代，
humanity has been in a dark age.
人性已在黑暗时代”。
And what I came to propose is
我要提议的是
that there is always a possibility of renewal
总是有重新开始的可能性
or we could say a resurrection.
或者说是复兴。
And how does that come?
那这个怎么到来呢？
That comes to the process of forgiveness.
它来自于宽恕的过程。
So forgiveness there's lots of talk,
有许多人在谈论宽恕，
it's not for them, it's for you.
不是为别人宽恕，而是为你自己。
But it really is for you in order to
宽恕真的是为你自己，
be able to continue on, on this road
让你能在这条路上走下去，
but not just you
但又不仅仅是你自己。
I always see myself traveling
我总是看到自己
in the middle of seven generations.
在7世代中穿行。
And so we know what happens when we carry emotional
我们知道当自己带着艰难情绪时，
difficulty to generations that come after us.
我们之后的几代人会遇到什么事。
So in order to, for humanity to keep traveling
所以，这是为了让人类继续行进，
through this dark era thousands of years now.
穿过这数千年以来的黑暗时代。
But the light is coming
但是光明正在来临，
he says, the light is coming
基督说，光明正在来临。
But in the meantime we have to be able to preserve
但与此同时，我们必须能维持，
not just ourselves
不仅是我们自己，
we can't think only in terms of one generation
我们不能只考虑一代人，
but in a way that radiates out through this
而要以某种方式
traveling with seven generations.
延伸穿过七代人。
And so I present that to us also.
我就向大家展示这些。
I loved what Joanna said a massive opening at the heart.
我喜欢乔安娜所说的，大大地敞开心扉。
And Pat what you said about the willingness to embrace
帕特，你所说的愿意去拥抱
those who have been perceived previously as adversaries.
那些过去被视为敌人的人。
One of the first… I've been doing dialogue work
我一直从事对话工作
as you said
正象你说的，
across the country and around the world
在全国各地，在全世界做对话工作。
And one of the first dialogues we ever did
一个我们最早做的对话工作
was in upstate New York.
是在纽约州的北部。
We had people of different political persuasion
我们请的人有不同的政治派别，
which sounds like a radical idea
这在当今这个
in our world now, in the current demonization.
妖魔化的世界，听起来很激进。
We had people of pretty much every ethnicity
我们请的人几乎来自
that exists in this country and religious background.
这个国家的所有种族和宗教背景。
And we were learning the principles of conflict resolution
我们当时正在学习解决冲突的原则，
except no one was listening to each other.
只是没人在听别人讲话。
And at the end of the day, we all sat on the floor.
一天结束时，我们坐在地板上。
And I made a simple suggestion
我提了一个简单的建议，
which is that we pause we breathe
让大家暂停一下，喘口气，
and we really listen to each other, tell our stories
真正聆听彼此，并讲出自己的故事。
Because in those stories is struggle,
因为故事中有挣扎,
everyone has a struggle,
每个人都有挣扎;
in those stories is grief,
故事中有悲伤，
especially now emerging from the pandemic,
特别是当下疫情肆虐时期；
in those stories is hope.
故事中也有希望。
And when we can hear each other's stories
当我们能听到彼此的故事，
we can find that kinship of loss
我们发现了分享痛
and that kinship of belonging.
和分享归属时产生的亲近感。
And so we did that all evening.
因此，我们一晚上都在做这件事。
In the next morning when we got up
第二天早上，当我们起床时，
someone in the group suggested we
团体里的一些人提议我们
sing a Zulu greeting chant.
唱祖鲁人的问候唱诵。
And then someone else suggested
另一些提议
we sing amazing grace.
我们唱奇异恩典。
I've had the experience in this last year and a half of
在过去一年半，我有个经历，
being awakened 2:30 in the morning
凌晨2点半我被叫醒，
and told that the fires were close the house.
被告知大火快烧到我的房子了。
Going up and feeling the ashes ranting down.
我起来并感到烟尘滚滚袭来。
Giving myself half an hour to run in and out of the house.
我有半个小时的时间，可以来回出入房子。
So I wouldn't be trapped to
这样我就不会去
get a few photo albums, a guitar, computer.
拿相册、吉他、电脑这样的东西。
I've had the experience of understanding
我有过了解到
that everything is impermanent
万事无常的经历，
everything turned to ashes.
万事万物最终都会变成灰烬。
And yet what survived that fire?
然而，什么从火灾中幸存下来了呢？
A whole mountainside, nothing of our structures,
整个山腰，我们的建筑荡然无存，
was a statue of Saint Francis and the earth flag.
只剩下一个圣方济各的雕像和一面地球旗。
Honestly,
老实说，
the fire went over the statue and over the earth flag.
大火绕过了雕像和地球旗。
And I took that as a message from our living planet
我把这当成是来自这个生生不息星球的信息，
that we have to find what Duane said about coming home
我们必须找到杜安所说的关于
to our inner dependence and our kinship of loss.
回到我们内在依存关系以及回到失去的亲情中去。
Dr King said that our goal is
金博士说我们的目标是
to create the beloved community on earth.
在地球上建立一个仁爱社区。
And this will require an inter change
这将需要我们内在
in the quality of our soul
灵魂上质的改变
and an outer change in the quantity
以及我们外在慈悲
of our compassionate action.
行动上量的改变。
And I love the quote from Paul Hawk and it's often…
我喜欢保罗·霍肯的话
I've never heard it really said
我从来没有当面听他这么说过，
but I wrote it, read it, and draw it back.
但我把它写下来，读一读，并背下来。
He says, it's imperative we remember that
他说，最重要的是我们要记住，
climate change isn't just happening to us
气候变化不仅仅是发生在我们身上，
it's happening for us.
它是为我们而发生的。
What does that mean?
这句话是什么意思呢？
It means that we're coming together,
它意味着我们正在团结起来，
we have to come together,
我们不得不团结起来，
no matter what travail we go through,
无论我们经历怎样的苦难，
no matter how much loss is coming,
无论有多少损失来临，
no matter how much catastrophic effect is happening,
无论有多少灾难性的影响正在发生着，
we will come together,
我们要团结起来，
because we must,
因为我们必须团结起来，
because we have to awaken and see our interrelatedness.
因为我们要觉醒，看到我们的相互关联性。
And our sense that
我们的感觉是，
as Dr King said in the darkest hour of his life
正如金博士在他生命中最黑暗的时刻所说的那样，
when he was praying at his kitchen table
当他正在厨房的餐桌前祈祷时，
before he got a phone call
他接到一个电话，
saying that his house was going to be bombed
说要把他的房子给炸了，
there in the Montgomery bus boycott
因为有个蒙哥马利公共汽车抵制行动。
He says whether we believe in a personal god
他说不论我们是相信个人上帝，
a force of love or an impersonal wrong,
还是相信爱的力量或者相信客观是非，
there is a cosmic companionship.
里面都存有宇宙情谊。
That is the phrase he used in 1956,
这是他在1956年用的短语，
a cosmic companionship
即宇宙情谊。
And we are not alone.
我们并不孤独。
It is in our destiny
在我们的天命里，
to evolve to this next level of our humanity.
要将人性进化到下一个层次。
God,
上帝，
great spirit,
伟大的神灵，
however you conceive of, the higher power is with us.
不管你怎么想，更高之力与我们同在。
What's really landing with me is
帕特，真正触动我的是
the word from you, Pat, co-witnessing.
你用的一个词——共同见证。
And I just want to take that in and hold that and
我只想把这句话即在心里，握住它，
be aware of my co-witnessing with you
并且意识到我正与你共同见证，
co-witnessing what you're saying
共同见证你所说的。
And the invitation to really hear each other
作为共同见证的一部分，
as part of that co-witnessing.
邀请大家真正倾听对方的声音。
In terms of what's needed,
就需要的东西而言，
what's needed now and these times?
当下这个时代需要什么？
I do a lot of work around resilience training.
我做了很多复原力培训工作。
And one of the practices I do is
其中我让大家做的一个练习是，
I invite people to hold their hands out
我邀请人们伸出双手，
and imagine that in one hand is a tennis ball
想象一只手里握着一个网球，
and in the other hand is a tomato.
另一只手握着番茄。
And invite you to do this if you like
如果愿意，我邀请你们来一起做，
you can just try it now
你现在就可以试试，
and anyone watching try this.
每一位正在看的观众也可以尝试。
Imagine the tennis ball what it feels like in your hand
想象网球在手的感觉，
and then squeeze,
然后捏它，
just squeeze gently,
就轻轻地捏着，
and then let go.
然后放开。
And you can hold the tomato and
现在想象手握番茄，
feel it in your hand and squeeze gently
感觉它在你的手中，轻轻地捏着，
and then let go
然后放开。
And then squeeze harder,
接着用力捏，
maybe squeeze both at the same time
可以双手同时攥捏，
and see what happens.
看看会发生什么。
I sometimes do this with a tennis ball and tomato,
我有时用真的网球和番茄来做这个练习，
but it is messy.
但会有些乱糟糟。
Resilience is often thought of it’s like that tennis ball
复原力常常被认为像网球那样，
that springs back into shape.
可以弹回原形。
And there's time when that's really handy
当我们遇到重击时，
when we've had a hard knock
有的时候这真的很管用。
We can spring back into shape afterwards
当我们感到被击倒时，
when we felt knocked down
我们可以在事后恢复状态，
when we can get back on our feet again
当我们可以重新站起来时，
or when you have that sense of
或者当你有那种感觉，
oh, I'm back to my old self again.
哦，我又回到原来的自己了。
1368：
But the thing about the tomato is that
但是，对于番茄来说，
if you did that in the right place
如果你在恰当的地方捏，
you can imagine maybe coming back 10 years later
你可以想象在十年后回来时，
and seeing tomatoes growing around you
看到番茄在你周围生长，
if you did it outside and there was good soil
如果你在室外做，而且那里有很好的土壤，
or if a bird picked up a bit of the tomato
或者有鸟叼起一块番茄，
and then deposited it somewhere.
然后把它丢到什么地方。
That tomato seeds have this incredible resilience
番茄的种子有不可思议的复原力，
that they can survive through
它们能度过最冷的寒冬，
the coldest of winters, through guts.
能通过消化道而生存下来。
And it's a different way of thinking about resilience.
这是一种思考复原力的不同方式。
And I'm just thinking Pat, about you rooting for collapse.
帕特，我在想关于你崩溃的观点。
And tomatoes won't grow
番茄不会生长，
unless there's collapse at the tomato.
它们只有破裂了才会生长。
That's what releases the seeds for future growth.
这就是为未来生长而破裂的种子。
And I guess what's needed now is
我觉得现在需要
to be aware of these different types of resilience
认识到这些不同的复原力，
that we will and our experiencing collapse around us.
我们将经历的崩溃以及我们正在经历的崩溃。
And working in organizations where
在组织中工作，
it just feels like it's all falling apart.
感觉一切都要崩溃了。
Collapse of our weather system.
还有气候系统的崩溃。
And I think one of the skills and skillfulness
我认为这里所需的一种技能、
and storylines it's needed is
技巧和故事情节是，
how can I plant seeds for future growth,
我们如何为未来的成长播种？
how can I tend to the seeds that have already been planted
我怎样照顾已经埋好的种子?
and how can I… even myself
我们怎么...即使是我自己，
sometimes I feel like a squash tomato on the floor
有时也会感觉像是地上那被捏碎的番茄，
when I have those moments,
当我有这些时刻的时候，
how can I in that moment say, okay,
我怎么能在那一刻说，好吧，
what can I do right now that will plant a seed
我现在能做什么，能为我明天
for my growing back in a different way tomorrow。
以不同的方式重新成长播下种子？
And you might think of that as bouncing forward
你可能认为这是一种向前的弹性，
that it's the resilience of life happening through us
这是通过我们发生的生命复原力，
like this is incredible power in nature.
象大自然中不可思议的力量。
I'm thinking Craig of your home burnt down
我在想，克里格，你的家烧光了，
but if you go back to that place a year from now
但是，如果你一年或者五年后，
or five years from now
回到那里，
there's this incredible vitality
那片土地会重新生长，
in the ground that grows back.
有不可思议的生命力。
And if we feel yeah we're part of this too.
如果我们感到，是的，我们也是其中之一。
That same story can happen through us too.
同样的故事会通过我们发生
And so I love this question what happens through you,
因此，我喜欢这个问题，什么会通过你发生？
how can life happen through us,
生命是怎么通过我们发生的？
how can the story of life happen through us,
生命故事是怎么通过我们发生的？
how can we play our part in that story.
我们在故事中怎么扮演自己的角色？
And once I really lean into that storyline it
当我真正沉浸在故事情节之中，
it changes what my life is about.
它改变了我对生活的看法。
And also that expression I'm rooting for collapse
同时，在“我支持崩溃”的表达方式里，
I can really see the wisdom in there
我真的能看到其中的智慧，
about how we play a role in
即我们如何在我们的选择中
our choices will influence what happens next.
发挥作用将影响接下来发生的事情。
Basically, we have to recognize that
基本上而言，我们认识到
we each have our individual superpowers
我们每个人都有自己个人的超能力
we have our own sets of relationships and sets of skills.
我们有自己的一套关系网和技能。
And we each need to find our particular place.
我们每个人都需要找到自己的一席之地。
So the individual is very important.
因此，个体很重要。
But recognizing that no individual
但是也要意识到个体
is going to solve this problem
不能解决这个问题，
and that it depends on us working together.
这有赖于我们共同努力。
And what it means is we can't get there simply
这意味着我们不能简单地
by eliminating our use of carbon,
通过消除碳使用而达成整体目标，
we cannot get there simply by eliminating any quality.
我们不能简单地通过牺牲任何品质来达成目标。
But what we have to do is
而我们要做的是
eliminating dependence on carbon while
消除我们对碳的依赖的同时，
we're eliminating our extreme and growing inequality.
消除日益严重和极端的不平等现象。
And while we are restoring the quality
当我们在恢复地球土壤的质量
and vitality of earth soils, restoring our aquifer.
和活力的同时，恢复地下蓄水层。
We have an infinite variety of things
我们有无数的事情
that we need to address together
需要共同解决，
which require specialized attention.
这些事情需要专门的关注。
But with a larger vision
但是在更大的愿景中，
realizing that when I'm working on my piece,
意识到当我做我这部分时，
I'm not competing with you,
我没有和你竞争，
we are part of the same process,
我们是同一过程的一部分，
and we have to bring all these pieces together
我们必须把所有这些部分以我们从未
in ways that we've never imagined before.
想象过的方式组合在一起。
And get this,
在做到这一点的过程中，
our whole education system is
我们的整个教育体系
designed to prevent the kind of learning
被设计成阻止这种学习，
that is most important to our future.
而这种学习对我们未来是最重要的。
If you believe a Boontoo
如果你相信布恩顿人，
and you're a villager in a Boontoo village
如果你是布恩顿村的村民，
well what that tells you is
那会告诉你，
that we need to organize as a community
我们需要组织成一个社区。
I mean this is a larger lesson now, too.
我的意思是，这也是一个更大的教训。
Because we organized around the power of government
因为，我们以前围绕政府权力而组织起来，
and now we organize around the power of corporations
而现在我们围绕公司权力而组织起来，
but for the future we seek,
但为了我们寻求的未来，
we have to organize around community.
我们必须围绕社区组织起来。
Communities of place
地方社区，
and people in traditional communities of place
传统地方社区中的人，
the ones that were most successful
那些最成功的人
were the ones that were very skilled
都是些技能非凡的人，
that when we get together for a meeting
当我们聚在一起开会时，
we know each other, we know each other very well
我们彼此了解，彼此非常了解，
we know each other’s superpowers.
我们知道每个人都有超能力。
So if we're having a problem with the agriculture,
如果我们有农业问题，
we turn to the person who's
我们向最擅长
the most skilled in agriculture for solutions;
农业的人寻求解决方案；
if we got a health problem,
如果我们有健康问题，
we turn to the person who's
我们会去找
the most skilled in that particular issue.
在这个特定领域最擅长的人。
It wasn't we have one president or we have one emperor
不像以前我们有一个总统或皇帝，
or whatever who makes all the decisions.
或一个做决定的人。
And again in the most successful communities
再一次，在最成功的社区中，
your leaders are not all men or they're not all women
领导者不都是男人，也不都是女人，
we're in this together and
我们在一起，
we pass the baton around depending on
我们根据我们的特殊需要和技能，
what our particular needs and skills
把接力棒传递下去，
are for whatever we're working on.
无论我们在做什么工作。
So for our final question
对最后一个问题，
we're going to go into a rapid round:
我们将快快谈一圈，
What is your vision of humanity's future?
你对人类未来的愿景是什么?
Are we going to make it as a species?
做为一个物种，我们会实现它吗？
And let's start this time with Pat
我们这次从帕特开始。
Well, at this point consciousness is the name of the game.
在这个点上，意识是这个游戏的名称。
And I also say I've had it with brilliant ideas and genius.
我也会说我已受够了那些绝妙的想法和天才，
I'm over it.
我受够了。
we don't know and so we have to reach beyond ourselves.
我们不知道，我们要去超越自身。
So what is that consciousness shift
那么，这种意识的转变是什么呢？
So I see it as again from indigenous perspective
我再次从原住民角度去看它。
that the history has been that
历史告诉我们，
we have been through worlds and we've lost worlds.
我们经历了很多世界，也失去了很多世界。
And so for my work I say either way,
从我的工作看，我会说任何一条路，
whether we're going to go off the cliff
无论是跌下悬崖，
or whether we stop short,
还是悬崖勒马，
I'm working for consciousness shift
我正为意识转变而工作
and I'm working for reparations.
而且正为修复而工作。
Because I believe that when that next world has to begin
因为我相信，当下一个世界
all the way over from the very very beginning again
必须从头重新开始时，
that we get to start from a different place
如果我们有不同的意识，
if we have a different consciousness
我们就会从不同的地方开始。
One dream I have also is I think about money
我的另一个梦关于钱，
money only can come from one place
钱只能来自一个地方，
money can only have ever come out of the earth
钱只能来自地球，
there's no other place for it to have come from.
没有其它地方可以产生钱。
So all this accumulation of wealth
所以所有这些财富的积累，
the hoarding of wealth
财富的囤积，
26 billionaires holding 50% of the world's wealth.
26个亿万富翁掌握着世界上50%的财富。
I see that as life being damned up
我认为那是生命被诅咒了，
and that life that has been extracted from earth
那些从地球、海洋、天空、
from ocean from sky from humans from animals
人类和动物中掠夺的生命
that life has to be released back into life.
必须被释放回生命中。
Life is screaming out for it.
生命正在为此大声疾呼。
And so I'm seeing how we're going to
我正看见我们
be able to make the communities
将如何建立社区，
such that it becomes joyful to release that life back into life
在这样的社区里，生命回归本然状态，
and that talks about a lot about relationship building
在这里有很多的关系建立、
trust and a true desire to continue forward and to live
信任和真实地渴望继续生活。
I know that after talking about grief and our kinship of loss
我知道在谈论悲伤和失去的亲情之后，
that it may seem strange to use the word joyful.
再用“快乐”这个词，可能会有些奇怪。
But I love Pat that you just used it and it evoked me
但是我喜欢帕特刚才用的词，它启发了我。
Winston Churchill during World War II
温斯顿·丘吉尔曾在二战期间，
talked about walking with destiny,
谈到了与命运同行，
his experience of walking with destiny.
他与命运同行的经历。
And he said that he thought that
他说到，他认为
courage was the most important virtue
勇气是最重要的美德，
because it made all the others possible.
因为勇气让所有的事情成为可能。
I would say that
我会说，
we are needing to choose to walk with destiny
我们需要选择与命运同行，
and to choose courage in its meeting strength of heart.
选择与内心力量相遇的勇气。
I have two grand babies, Zady and Odie.
我有两个孙子，泽迪和欧迪。
They’re just two and three.
一个两岁，一个三岁。
They will be about 80 years old at the turn of the century
新纪元来临时，他们将80多岁，
which means that it's imminent.
这意味着时间已迫在眉睫。
We can touch it,
我们可以触碰到它，
we're living right there.
我们正生活在其中。
So, I have a new book
我有本新书，
that's coming out entitled choose hope - you matter
书名是《选择希望 – 你很重要》。
And I love saying it because I can go choose hope
我喜欢这么说，因为我能去选择希望，
and then I can reach to the other and bow and say
我也能接触到别人，鞠个躬，然后说，
you matter, your life matters,
你很重要，你的生命很重要，
your dignity matters,
你的尊严很重要，
your choices matter.
你的选择很重要。
The Dalai Lama says that
正如DL喇嘛所说，
our world is a spiritual democracy in sense.
我们的世界是在某种意义上是一个灵性民主的世界。
It's the accumulation of all of
这个世界是我们所有的
our consciousness and action, so you matter.
意识和行动的累积，所以你很重要。
And choosing to be hopeless is kind of the booby prize
选择无望是一种诱饵，
in that the mind gets to be right
因为头脑认为其理所当然，
but it disempowers us.
但它却剥夺了我们的权力。
Choosing hope is an orientation of the soul
选择希望是灵魂的方向，
a dimension of the human spirit
是人类灵性的维度，
that is not dependent upon external circumstances.
它不依赖于外界环境。
And so on behalf of the children
因此，代表孩子
and the children's children and our descendants
和孩子的孩子及我们的子孙后代，
we need to choose hope
我们需要选择希望
to commit ourselves to personal leadership with sole force
以独有的力量致力于个人领导力，
to help reduce climate change and restore the earth
助力减少气候变化的影响和修复地球，
to advance justice and human rights for all people
促进所有人的公正和人权，
and to cultivate peace within ourselves
去培养内在的宁静
between each other and on the earth so that
在这个地球上与其它生命和平共处，这样，
as Dr King says
如金博士所说，
the darkest hour of the night is the hour before the dawn
黑夜中最暗的时刻是黎明前那一刻，
this is the hour before the dawning.
现在正是黎明前那一刻。
I believe that
我相信这一点，
I choose to believe that, I have no proof of that
我选择相信这一点，虽然我没有证据，
it's a stance.
这是我的立场。
So that 200 years from now,
因此，从现在起200年，
historians will look back and say that
历史学家将回看并会说，
our earth was going through a dark time,
我们的地球曾穿过黑暗时刻，
life on earth was threatened,
那时地球上的生命受到威胁，
human civilization was threatened,
人类文明受到威胁，
but there was a great turning
但是有大转折，
in which individuals awakened to
在大转折中个体在他们
the light of their own consciousness.
自己的意识之光照耀下觉醒了。
And in which millions of people joined together
在大转折中，数以百万计的人为了一个
for a love-based worldwide rising
基于爱的世界性崛起而联合起来，
that created the conditions for
这为和平、正义和
peace, justice and restoring the earth.
地球修复创造了条件。
That is a prayer.
这是祈祷。
May it peace out.
愿世界和平。
Duane
I don't know if we're going to make it.
我不知道我们是否会成功。
It's a very precarious time in humanity's future.
现在是人类未来岌岌可危的时候。
And, I think if we're going to make it
我认为，如果我们要实现它，
we're going to have to step up consciously,
我们必须有意识地采取行动，
we're going to either choose it, or we're going to lose it.
我们要么选择它，要么失去它。
And I see three major pathways ahead.
我看到前面有三条主要路径。
One is a path of extinction.
一条是灭绝之路。
We just continue on as we have been
我们只是一意孤行，
and we unravel the earth ever further.
进一步让地球瓦解。
We experience breakdown, collapse and
我们经历崩溃和坍塌，
then the functional extinction of the species
然后是物种的功能性灭绝，
doesn't mean we have to all disappear.
这并不意味着我们都会消失。
But the functional extinction of the species
但是作为进化力量的物种的
as a force for evolution can end.
功能性灭绝可能会结束。
And that's a very real possibility
考虑到我们现在的轨道，
given the track we're on right now.
这是一个非常现实的可能性。
Another track is on authoritarianism.
另一条路是独裁主义。
And we can see the rise of
我们能看到世界上
the authoritarian mindset in the world.
独裁主义观念的升起。
Many people are ready to
许多人已经准备好
surrender their personal freedoms
为了一个专制世界的安全和
for the safety and security of an authoritarian world.
保障而放弃他们的个人自由。
And that world as well,
那个世界也会
takes us towards the collapse of the world
带我们走向我们过去
that we have known in the past.
所知道的世界的崩溃
A third world is the one we've been speaking about here
第三条路是我们正在这里谈论的，
it's the great turning, it's the great transformation.
那就是大转折，大转变。
It's waking up to a new way of being on the earth
它正在唤醒地球上一种新的存在方式，
moving from our adolescence as a species
从我们作为一个物种的青春期
and into our early adulthood, into our maturity.
进入我们的成年早期和成熟期。
And moving from a me orientation to a we orientation.
从一个由“我”主导到“我们”主导。
How can I heal and care for the wellbeing of all life?
我如何疗愈和关心所有生命的福祉?
And that orientation I think is
我认为这个方向
going to emerge out of collapse as well.
也会从崩溃中浮现出来。
All three futures contain breakdown and collapse.
三种未来都包含分解和崩溃。
Tthe question is …given that we're breaking down
假设我们正在分崩离析，
given that the world is collapsing
假设世界正在崩溃，
what will we choose, then
那么，我们将选择什么？
will we choose life? will we choose a great turning?
我们将选择生命吗？我们将选择大转折吗？
So this is in my estimation the time of
所以这是我估计
the most pivotal choice in the last 10,000 years.
最近一万多年来最关键的选择时刻。
May we choose life.
愿我们选择生命。
The dream is that we discover
梦想是我们在相互依存中
our potential in our interdependence
发现我们的潜力，
and that we create...
我们也去创造...
But some of us are calling an ecological civilization
一些人在召唤生态文明，
which recognizes the interdependence of life.
这种生态文明意识到生命间的相互依赖。
And our fundamental dependence on
我们依赖于地球的福祉，
the wellbeing of earth and on one another.
也依赖于彼此间的福祉。
And that we create a world,
我们创建了一个世界，
in which we recognize that our human responsibility
在其中，我们意识到人类的责任
is not to control and dominate earth
不是去控制和主宰地球，
which is impossible,
这是不可能的，
that's the path to self destruction.
这是通往自我摧毁的道路。
But that we are here to partner with earth,
而我们在这里是与地球成为伙伴，
to support the inherent processes of life
来支持生命的内在过程，
and deepen our understanding of life and create a future
加深我们对生命的理解，创造一个未来，
in which we recognize that it is in fact
让我们认识到事实上
our spiritual understanding
我们的灵性理解
and growth that is the purpose.
和成长才是目的。
That we definitely have material needs.
我们当然有物质需求。
And our goal must be to learn,
我们的目标必须是学习，
to meet our material needs in ways that
以符合我们相互爱和关怀、
are consistent with our mutual love and caring
地球福祉、
and the wellbeing of earth
我们自己福祉和
as well as the wellbeing of ourselves
支持我们持续学习的方式
and the support of our continued learning
来满足我们的物质需求。
It requires recognizing that
这需要意识到我们目前
we currently organize around this pursuit of money
围绕着对金钱的追求进行组织，
which is, you think about it, is really pretty stupid,
当你想到这点，是非常愚蠢的，
because money is nothing but a number
因为金钱什么都不是, 它只是一个数字，
that has no existence outside of the human mind.
不存在于人的意识之外。
And so we're destroying life to
我们正在摧毁生命
grow these numbers that don't even exist
去增加那些根本不存在的数字，
in a way it's incredible.
这令人难以置信。
Cryptocurrency is the ultimate example,
加密货币是一个极致的例子
the enormous environmental burden it creates.
它产生了巨大的环境负担。
And what is the product,
它的产品是什么？
it's nothing but another set of new numbers
什么都不是，只是在电脑硬盘上的
on a computer hard drive.
另一套新数字而已。
Yeah it really raises a question.
是的，它的确带来了问题。
Are we in fact an intelligent species?
我们真的是智能物种吗？
Potential to become an intelligent species,
只是有潜力变成智能物种，
but we have yet to prove it.
但我们还没证明这点。
Now in terms of the human future,
现在，就人类的未来而言，
what will be the human future?
人类的未来会怎样？
I can't predict that.
我预测不了。
If you ask me as an objective analyst,
如果把我当成客观分析师来问这个问题，
I would say
我会说
there's absolutely no hope for the human future
人类的未来绝对没有希望，
we are so far behind,
我们太落后了，
we've got our stories so wrong,
我们的故事大错特错，
our relationships so wrong that we might as well give it up.
我们的关系如此错误，以至于我们还不如放弃它。
It's all over.
这一切都结束了。
But I also know,
但是，我也知道，
from what I've seen and experienced in my life
根据我在生活中的所见所闻，
that we have potentials that we have not yet actualized
我们有尚未实现的潜力，
and that we also have potential to shift very very quickly
我们也有潜力迅速转变，
if in a sense we choose to do so
如果在某种意义上我们选择去这么做，
and that is the challenge of this moment
这是此刻的挑战，
the challenge of our time indeed
我们这个时代的挑战。
So I would like to give the final word to Joanna,
我希望由乔安娜做最后发言，
which means Chris, would you like to speak now
所以，克里斯，你能先讲吗？
And then we'll hand it over to our revered elder.
然后，请我们尊敬的长者发言。
Thank you, thank you so much.
谢谢，非常感谢你。
Well I just think the fact that you're asking
我觉得你问这个问题的事实本身，
this question shows that we're really in danger.
表明我们已然处于危险之中。
And so that's what I would focus on.
所以这是我想关注的。
I don't know the answer.
我不知道答案为何。
But even that
即便我们
it's possible that we are heading over the cliff and
可能正在走向悬崖...
One orientation I find helpful is just…
我发现一个有帮助的方向是…
I can hold out hand and say
我可以伸出手，说，
each digit is a different way things can go.
每个手指代表一个可以走的不同道路。
And we can say what's the worst that can happen?
我们可以说最坏的情况是什么？
The worst that can happen has been described.
最糟糕的事情已经被描述出来了。
We could go over the edge of a cliff,
我们可能走到了悬崖的边缘，
we could become functionally extinct.
我们可能会功能性灭绝。
What's the best that can happen
能发生的最好的事情是什么？
That's much more exciting.
这更令人兴奋。
But what's most likely to happen.
但是最可能发生什么呢？
I'd say on the whole
我会说从总体而言，
it's more lightly that things are going downhill
事情正在走下坡路更轻松，
but it's how we respond to that makes a difference
但我们如何应对才是关键，
and so it's the hope.
这也是我们的希望。
I'd say it's more what do you hope for
更重要的是你希望什么,
do I hope that things will work out?
我希望问题得到解决吗？
Of course I do.
我当然想。
And then how can I be active that way?
那么，我怎么积极起来？
So that's what I'm really interested in.
这是我真正感兴趣的。
And I love the title of your book, Craig
克里格，我喜欢你书的书名，
Choose hope, Choose you.
《选择希望, 选择你》。
So the question is a trigger and a warning.
因此，这个问题是触发器，也是个警告。
And it just really brings me into
这恰恰让我真正意识到
acknowledgment of what we face.
我们所面临的问题。
And the great turning is about turning up
大转折是关于现身，
and being clear what I want to turn away from
明确我想从什么事情离开，
and what I want to turn towards.
并转向哪些事情。
Thank you, thank you again.
谢谢，再次感谢你们！
And Joanna the last word is yours.
乔安娜，请你来说结束语。
Well, as the elder among us and I am in my nineties now.
作为我们之中的年长者，我现在已经90多岁了。
And the astonishment for me,
令我惊讶的是,
the main astonishment is a sense of gratitude
最让我惊讶的是一种感恩之情
that floods me, coming surprisingly,
它淹没着我，涌向我,
at moments I cannot explain it
有时我难以解释它，
but I can try.
但我可以试试。
I would not want to miss this moment on earth,
我不想错过在地球上的这一刻，
it is wondrous to me
对我来说，
the very questions that we have posed and answered
我们提出并回答了我们从彼此那里听到的问题，
what we've heard from each other.
真是太棒了！
Oh, my god.
哦，上帝。
Would you want to miss being here
在这个星球上，作为人类来经历
when this incredible story of being human on this planet?
这个难以置信的大转折故事，你难道想错过这里吗？
How far back it goes and that we are seriously
我们上一次从世界各地
sitting together around the world?
很严肃地坐在一起是什么时候？
Looking at this could be very easily curtains for us.
讨论这些事情对我们来说很容易。。。（斟酌中）
And when I first read
当我第一次读到
what I report of IPCC that scared me.
联合国政府间气候变化专门委员会报告，它吓到我了。
And I saw that…
我看到了
I was then the next day
接下来那天，
in a meditation center at Spare Rock and
我在斯巴·洛克的冥想中心，
doing Buddhist mindfulness practice.
做佛教正念练习。
And I was walking along,
我四处走动，
trying to keep my mind on just the present moment
尽力将我的念头只关注在当下，
just now what's happening now, not conjecturing.
仅仅关注当下发生了什么，而不是推测。
But my mind was caught up with
但我的脑海里充斥着
a personal embarrassment
一种个人的尴尬，
something very minor and I couldn't get off it.
有一件非常小的事，让我无法释怀。
And I thought, oh, there I should know,
我想，哦，我应该知道，
I should just know what to do with this
我应该知道该为这做些什么，
just note it and go move on.
只是留意它，然后继续前行。
And then a thunderous voice came up my left side
然后，一个雷鸣般的声音从我左边响起，
and it said just fall in love with what is
它说：“就爱上本来的样子吧！”。
And as I heard that,
当我听到这个，
I saw on the path ahead of me
我看到眼前的小路上，
two curtains closing.
有两扇“窗帘”关上了。
And I knew that one
我知道其中一个
was the IPCC report on climate catastrophe
是IPCC报告中的气候灾难；
and the other was the election in Brazil of Bolsonaro,
另一个是巴西博罗索纳的竞选,
with his promise to
他承诺用
liquidate the cash in on the lungs of the planet.
地球的肺兑现现金。
And since then,
从那时开始，
what that has a bread in me is
我内心深处的想法是
taking the possibility of the end quite seriously
要认真对待结局的一切可能性，
and also being totally in love with this world
同时全然地热爱这个世界，
and being so grateful that I didn't miss this moment.
非常感激我没有错过这个时刻。
A conversation like this that you've brought together
玛蒂，像这样的谈话，
Mattie really, we're asked,
你把我们聚到一起，问我们问题，
I wouldn't have missed this for the world.
我不会错过这个世界的。
So all I know is that… can learn to say
我所知的就是，我会这样说，
be here now,
活在当下，
in this now.
活在此刻。
In this now where we feel our vitality
活在我们感受到活力的当下，
where we feel possibility with our hearts break open.
活在我们能敞开我们破碎的心，去感受可能性的当下。
And this is so rich that I find myself imagining
当下太丰富了，我发现自己在想象，
that in Buddha field surround the universe,
在环绕宇宙的佛国中，
there are people lining up to get an incarnation on earth now.
有许多人正在排队要转世到地球。
We aren't missing it, we're here.
我们不会错过机会，我们就在这里。
Listen what we've harvested from each other,
听听我们从彼此谈话中的收获，
the love we've heard.
我们听到了爱。
It's service to our loyalty and thanksgiving for life itself
它服务于我们对生命本身的忠诚和感恩，
and even willing…
甚至是心甘情愿…
Love so great that we can see
爱如此之大，
the shameful elements, we can see it all.
它让我们愿意看到羞耻心，看到所有的羞耻心。
So, that gratitude is my gratitude for each one of you.
这感恩是我对你们每一位的感恩。
Each one of you has fed me.
你们每个人都供养过我。
And I, where I hang out with this gratitude is in uncertainty
我带着这种感恩行走在不确定中
the gift of it
它带来的礼物是…
another face at the other side of uncertainty is now.
在不确定的另一面是当下。
It has three letters, n o w.
它由三个字母组成：N、O、W。
Now, we are in this now.
当下，现在我们就在其中。
And when entering that,
而且，当我们进入当下
we find a spiritual fountain,
我们就找到了灵性的源泉，
we find a holy place,
我们找到了圣地，
we find trust,
我们找到了信任，
we find gladness,
我们找到了欢乐，
and we find gratitude that's where I am
我们找到了感恩，那是我所在之地。
We're all bowing with love and prayer.
我们都用爱和祈祷鞠躬。
I feel it in each of you.
我在你们每个人身上都感受到了它。
I wanted to thank Craig the first to use
我要感谢克雷格第一个
in our knowledge the great turning as a phrase
在我们的知识体系中使用“大转折”一词。
Thank you so much, great to meet each one of you.
太谢谢你们了，能见到你们太好了！
Thank you.
谢谢!
I'm really pleased to be alongside into co-witness.
我很高兴能和你们一起共同见证。
Based on this experience,
基于这次经历，
I am eager to continue working with you.
我渴望继续与你们合作。
Much love to each.
将爱带给各位。
And thank you Mattie.
谢谢玛缇!
Deep appreciation to each and every one of you
深深地感激你们每一位，
my heart is so full.
我心如此充实。
Okay my love's pouring out.
我的爱也在涌出。
Go well.
各位保重！
An abundance of blessings to each and every one of you.
深深地祝福你们每一位!
And I hope to see you again soon.
希望尽快再见到你们!